Preliminary Inventory of the Barbara Nawratowicz Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Barbara Nawratowicz papers
1952-2000
2005C32
Nawratowicz, Barbara
3 manuscript boxes (1.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Broadcast scripts, memoranda, letters, clippings, photographs, and sound recordings, relating to Radio Free Europe broadcasts to Poland.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2005.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Radio Free Europe Polish section music director.
Scope and Content of Collection
Broadcast scripts, memoranda, letters, clippings, photographs, and sound recordings, relating to Radio Free Europe broadcasts to Poland.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Radio Free Europe.; Radio broadcasting--Poland.; Phonotapes.
Collection Contents
- Correspondence, clippings, and RFE/RL Polish service transcripts (Box 1)
- Clippings and pamphlets
- Sound recordings
  - Music recordings, undated (Box 3)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005567
    Box spine label reads: C82670 KURANT
  - Piosenki Radiowe RFE music recordings, undated (Box 2)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005570
    PIOSENKI RADIOWE RFE Strone - A (1) W.Krajewski - "Szumia fale Baltyku" 23 35" (2) Same as number 1 ----2'40" lepsze (3) W Krajewski-"Dla mej matki piesn" 2'53" - + (4) J.Koryzme-"Nowyszal-bossa nova"-3'20 (5) K. Kaliszewska-"Il mondo"-3'20" -+ (6) K. Kaliszewska (J.Katelbach?)-"By-by Billy - 2'24" (7) Muzyczny przerywnik-Mario Sarachino 2'07" (8) Same as number 7 - + - 2'10" (9) K. Kaliszewska-"Wenecje"-2'43" (10) B. Nawratowicz-"zostah tu" - 1'50"
  - Radio Free Europe voice recordings, undated (Box 3)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005571
    Box spine label has the recording as C34587; reel flange label has the recording as C79709
  - Polish service broadcast recording, circa 3 May 1952 (Box 3)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005572
    Concerns the audio inauguration of Radio Free Europe
  - Piosenki Wybrzeza music recordings, undated (Box 2)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005573
    Piosenki Wybrzeza 1970 - B (1) "Co sie komu nalezv - Melodeklama B.Jerke - 1'30" (2) "Wziac to czego niema"-J.Marchw winski - 1'05" (3) "Gomulka" -W.Krajewski B.Jerks 2'42"x (4) "17go grudnia 70go"-piesn stocznicwcow -W.Krajewski -2'30" xxx (5) "Baltyk" -B.Nawratowicz-3'09" (zryw Wybrzeza) (6) "16-go grudnia roku pamietnego"-Gierek! -B.Jerke x chor 3'35" / -a- strona Muzyka - .Sarachino
  - Radio Free Europe voice recording, undated (Box 3)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005574
    Box spine label has the tape as C44432; reel flange label has the tape as C62073
  - Broadcast program, 31 December 1956 (Box 3)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005575
    REWIA SYLWESTROWA. Tape C60431. See tape information sheet inside of the box.
  - Piosenki music recordings, undated (Box 2)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005576
    See tape information sheet inside of the case.
  - Radio Free Europe broadcast recordings, 15-22 November 1953 (Box 3)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005577
    POLACY NA ZACHODZIE. See tape information sheet inside of the box.
  - Piosenki music recordings, undated (Box 2)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005578
    Case spine label reads: POSENKI
  - Radio Free Europe voice recordings, undated (Box 3)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005579
    Tape C63442
  - Dog songs, undated (Box 3)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005580
    Two songs related to dogs. The first is a song where the melody is performed by dog barks. The second is "(How Much Is) That Doggie in the Window." Tape C77993
  - Radio Free Europe / Radio Liberty music recording, 12-24 December 1986 (Box 3)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005581
    Christian Meditations. Tape A81821
  - Sound recording C87456, undated (Box 3)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005582
    Tape C87456. It sounds like a derivative of a disc record.
  - Radio Koledy with Rod Nocnev sound recording, undated (Box 2)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005583
  - Sound recording C87457, undated (Box 3)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005584
    Sounds like a derivative of a disc record.
  - Music and interview sound recording, undated (Box 2)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005585
  - Sound recording C87458, undated (Box 3)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005586
    The tape sounds like a derivative of a disc record.
  - Sound recording C87459, undated (Box 3)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005587
    The program sounds like a derivative of a disc record.
  - Piosenki Radiowe RWE music recordings, undated (Box 2)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005588
  - Sound recording C87460, undated (Box 3)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005589
    The program sounds like a derivative of a disc record. See tape inventory in the box.
  - Sound recording C87461, undated (Box 3)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005590
    The program sounds like a derivative of a disc record. See tape information sheet inside of the box.
  - RWE sound recording, undated (Box 2)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005591
    Names listed on the cassette sleeve: Nowak, Walesa, Karstwie, Stroba, Ttum, Robert Power
  - Przy stoliku artystycznym, 25 December 1956 (Box 3)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005592
    Tape B89814. See tape information sheet inside of the box.
  - Sound recording C34057, 5-6 December 1991 (Box 2)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005593
    See tape information sheet inside of the box.
  - Sound recording of various speeches, undated (Box 2)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005594
  - Radio Free Europe / Radio Liberty Polish service light music sound recording, undated (Box 2)
    Use copy reference number: 2005c32_a_0005595
    This tape is a dub of tapes U13543 and U13475